The Princess Sapphire
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Princess Knight,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Eleventh Episode
The Spirit of Sleep
Sapphire, are you coming to play?
Hello, Tink!
- Let's go!
- Prince!
Why that sneaky look?
- Sneaky look?!
- He's not doing anything wrong.
Don't you remember that you
are on vacation? You can play here!
- What?!
- Great!
I'm on vacation!
We can have fun!
Now that you are far from the
palace, don't let yourself go too much!
Remember the promises
that you made to your mother?
The first is to continue
to be good!
And what is the second?
The second is...
To be patient
during this week of vacation.
...and curb my spirit
of adventure.
- Don't forget it!
- Then, goodbye, Opal!
That was a close call! And who is this running
into me?! Help!
Esteemed Garigori, do you happen to know
where the Prince is?
Doctor, does this seem like
the time to come disturbing?
It doesn't matter. I have something
too important to report.
You can find the Prince
on the hill,
but mind, next time,
not to be so early!
Sapphire, look at what a beautiful landscape!
We are the squires of the King!
How heavy this pleasure weighs!
- Isn't that the King's throne?
- Yes, it is my father's.
I wonder what is happening...
Your Highness! Prince Sapphire!
Please, return immediately
to your residence.
No, because right now I'm playing.
You must obey me, Your Highness!
- What a pity...!
- No! No! No!
I don't want to wear it!
Why do I have to put on this dress?
It's for the ceremony you will have to
go through because the King is sick.
- Who will I receive?
- Lord Plastic.
Lord Plastic?!
Do you mean Duralumin's son?
Yes, that stupid son of his!
Quiet! If the Grand Duke hears you
talking like that, he'll make you pay!
His promotion is being celebrated:
after eight years in first grade, he was
promoted to second grade...!
Eight years for him to pass
first grade?!
Please don't laugh!
His Excellency
the Grand Duke Duralumin!
He is proud of his son
You didn't hurt yourself, Plastic?
Don't worry, everything is fine!
Come on, now go up the grand staircase
and greet them as they taught you.
Show everyone that you are
much better than Sapphire.
Nylon, did you teach him
the protocol?
- Yes, perfectly!
- Here he is.
Hi, Plastic! How's it going?
- Hi! - Prince, I ask you
to receive my son...
...according to tradition.
- I wanted to congratulate him.
Well, I thank you on his
behalf! Did you hear, Plastic?
- Answer the Prince.
- I'm going to answer! I'm going!
Stop! You are not
going the right way!
To get to the Prince,
you must turn to the right!
- Oh, no!
- To the right...
What did you teach him?!
I did my best!
There is nothing to laugh about!
Let's skip the
formalities and go play.
Grand Duke, I'm
taking Plastic to play!
He who laughs last laughs best,
Prince Sapphire!
Remember that, during the meal,
you must behave properly at the table!
You must use a fork and knife,
not your hands,
you must remain seated
and not pick your nose!
And don't throw breadcrumbs!
You must che...
Chew with your mouth closed, don't make
rude noises and don't start crying!
Damn, what a struggle!
My nose!
Damn, what a struggle
teaching this blockhead!
Did you get all of that through your thick skull?
- I am so sorry, Grand Duke!
- What are you doing, you complete idiot?
I was just pleasantly surprised
by your son's intelligence!
It's true! My son, after all,
is very intelligent!
I propose a toast
to Plastic's promotion! Bravo!
- Bravo!
I will not allow Sapphire
to sit on the throne.
Even if he pretends to be
a boy, she is a girl!
And since the law of this land
forbids a girl...
...to ascend the throne,
if I manage to get rid of the Prince,
then the throne will be Plastic's!
In fact, since I
am the King's only brother,
you have every right to it,
my son.
Should people take him
for a blockhead? No!
I will seat him on the throne
at all costs!
Plastic, where are you going? I'm coming with you!
Ehi, Plastic! Wait for me!
Where are you going? Why don't we play?
Since you're here,
let's play together, shall we?
How beautiful! I like these
so much! They are so good!
I want to take them!
It's a painting! You
can't eat painted things!
- I want to eat it!
- This strawberry looks real..
...because it is painted very well,
but you can't pull it off of there!
- I want to eat it! I want it!
- Don't throw a tantrum!
That is a painting! Oh, good
heavens, now he got angry!
I apologize!
Plastic, come back!
Sorry!
I want to eat it!
I want the strawberries!
It's impossible! It's
summer now, Plastic!
Strawberries only
grow in spring!
I want a strawberry!
Grand Duke! Your son will be
able to eat strawberries, even if...
Do you mean we can
get some strawberries?
Absolutely! In the middle of the
woods, strawberries also grow in summer!
Go pick them right now!
You will have them sooner than you think.
I sent some
soldiers to pick them.
I told them that
this spoiled boy...
...who is asking for strawberries
out of season is Prince Sapphire.
You did well.
What is this noise?
They said that whoever returns with the
strawberries will get a handsome reward.
- I will get that reward!
- No, I'll be the one to win it!
- I will find them!
- That prize will be mine!
- Who is pushing me?
- Let's go!
- Help! Fire!
- Run away!
Help!
Watch where you're going?!
Run! Run!
- Help! A monster!
- Run away!
Another monster!
Attack it!
Tell the truth: you didn't
expect these wonders, did you?
- But that's the devil!
- Who could it be?
Fools! Your weapons
are useless against me,
spirit of sleep! I will punish you
for staying awake tonight!
- Wake up, sprite!
- Here I am!
- Give me the sleep powder!
- Right away!
Powder of anger,
powder of tears,
powder of laughter,
powder of sleep!
Here it is! To you, little brother!
Now I will punish you! Fall asleep!
I can't keep
my eyes open...
The powder has no effect on me,
because I am an angel.
No one can resist sleep!
Who sent you to disturb
the peace of the forest tonight?
It was Prince Sapphire!
Suddenly he said...
..that he wanted to eat
some strawberries.
Prince Sapphire... I know him,
because he often comes to play.
Hey, sprite, how can I punish him?
Now, my dear Plastic.
Have a little patience!
Let's do a test.
Let me see
how you look on the throne.
You are incompetent!
I told you to sit on the throne!
Oh, you look so good
on that throne!
It seems made just for you!
One of these days, you will be sitting
there with the crown on your head!
And it will be all thanks to me!
Yes, mother, I will try to
be diligent! Just as you want!
Don't worry!
I will be good.
I won't get angry! I won't fight!
Spoiled prince! The spirit of
sleep has come to punish you...
...for your tantrums, which have
disturbed the peace of the forest!
Damn!
He is fast asleep.
...and I certainly cannot punish someone
who is sleeping! I'll have to wake him up!
And I will do just... that!
- Hey! Who is it?!
- I am the spirit of sleep!
I will make sure that you
can no longer sleep! There!
Why do you want to give me this punishment?
Don't pretend you don't know!
You woke up
the entire forest!
- Take this!
- No, it's not true!
- Didn't you want the strawberries?
- I assure you, I didn't ask for them!
May I know who wanted them,
then?
Well, you see...
I can't tell you!
- You're making fun of me, aren't you?
- What?!
If he won't say it, I will! It was
Plastic who wanted the strawberries!
Why did you tell him?
Good! And so it was
Plastic! I must go punish him!
Look, if you do anything to
Plastic, I won't forgive you!
Get out of the way!
Goodbye, little one!
- No, wait!
- Then so much the worse for you!
Spirit of the wind!
See how it doesn't pay
to go against me?
If you want war,
you'll have it! Take this!
And this!
Take that!
I won't continue! I promised my
mother that I wouldn't get angry.
- Help!
- If you hadn't wanted to hit me,
- you wouldn't have fallen.
- Poor elf!
Hey! Aren't you ashamed to mistreat
such a small child?
I didn't want to mistreat him! He suddenly
tried to hit me,
so I took a step to the side
and he fell!
Well done, little elf!
Anyway,
he deserves a punishment too!
I will make sure
that he doesn't wake up again!
I think he has lost consciousness.
Alright, I will forgive him!
Come with me!
Here I am!
I want to eat strawberries!
There he is! Did you see? It's that one over there!
- Grand Duke! Little Grand Duke!
- Who wants me?
Little Grand Duke! Tiny Grand Duke!
But... But who is it?!
Hey, spoiled brat! Do you know
that they ruined the sleep...
...of all the forest inhabitants
because of your tantrums?
What's there to laugh about?
As a punishment
for your insolence,
I will stop you from sleeping forever!
Plastic! What happened to you,
my son?
The soldiers didn't
find the strawberries.
Forget about
this nonsense!
There's something wrong with Plastic!
Yes, I know. It's his
head that's the problem.
Idiot!
It is beyond my power
to cure an idiot!
I'll take care of curing you!
Now close your eyes gently! You are sleepy!
You are getting sleepier and sleepier!
You are so sleepy! You
can't wait to go to bed!
I command you to close
those goddamned eyes!
Obey!
Come on, my dear child! Close them!
- Is Plastic here?
- What do you want, Prince?
Duralumin, perhaps I can cure him.
Just a moment!
- Opal!
- Your Highness, where do you want to go?
I must go into the forest
to look for the spirit of sleep
I won't let you go! It could
do to you what it did to Plastic!
Everything will be fine.
Plastic cannot stay like this.
Do you know that Plastic
is your enemy?
It's true!
He is the son of Duralumin
...and the Grand Duke wants him to
ascend the throne in your place!
- You know it well! Don't help him!
- Enough!
Spirit of sleep!
Spirit of sleep, where are you?
Where are you, spirit? Little spirit!
Spirit of sleep!
- Spirit of sleep, please!
- What do you want?
Have you come to get
revenge for the other night?
Darkness, fall! - I didn't come
to get my revenge!
I cannot fight
if it isn't dark.
And now it's pitch black!
More brushwood! Yes!
Make him dance some more!
- A little more!
- Enough!
Enough! Stop! Enough!
Please, enough! Enough!
Please, turn Plastic
back to how he was!
- No way!
- I am so sorry...
...about the soldiers.
You're right, I know.
You're saying that to me
because you're so afraid of me!
But you can't... Oh, no! I
promised not to get angry!
- Pixie, teach him a little lesson.
- At your command!
I slept...
Right, now I remember! You
were the one who put me to sleep!
- And who the hell are you?
- That's what I'm asking you.
- You are very impertinent!
- No, you're the impertinent one!
You are very impertinent!
How is it that Sapphire takes all
of this and hasn't gotten angry yet?
I get it!
In those jars there
is magic powder!
What a coward! It's
unbelievable that he's a Prince!
I need the anger powder. Which
one is it? Ah, here, it's this one!
Now I feel really angry!
Do you think it's over? Look!
Listen to me!
You don't even have the
strength to stand on your feet!
Are you still provoking me?
Too bad for you, spirit of sleep!
I will challenge you to a duel!
Well? Where did
you put all your fight?
Take this! And this! And this!
Sprite, help!
Now let's settle the
score... Look up there!
Now will you come and cure Plastic?
No! It's useless to threaten me!
Then tell me how
I can cure Plastic!
If you ask me like
that, I will never tell you!
Tell me, I beg you!
If you do what I ask
of you, then I'll tell you!
- I accept!
- Then kneel on the ground and beg me!
Do you really want me
to get down on my knees?
Just as I said:
kneel and beg me!
What's the matter? You can't do it?
A Prince never stoops
to such things!
I beg you,
show me what I can do.
How amusing! A Prince
kneeling before me!
Tell me if he looks like a Prince to you!
And he's begging me, too!
- Now I...
- Isn't this enough for you?
Well, now I'll tell you.
But you must be crazy to do
such things for another person.
He is a human being.
My poor son!
- I can cure him!
- What is that jar?
If you hurt my baby...
This is the powder that will make
him go back to how he was before.
He has woken up!
I am happy to see
that you are well again!
Your Highness, I have
no words to thank you!
Silence! What I did I
certainly didn't do for you.
Grand Duke, here is the powder
that always keeps one awake.
Do you want him to be sick again?
But I got it to put it
on the Prince! What do you think?
- On Sapphire?
- Yes! There is no need
...to thank him too much just
because he saved your son.
I was in the forest while he
was asking the spirit what to do...
...and I saw
that he didn't try all that hard!
Do not forget
that, as long as the Prince is alive,
your son will not be able to
sit on the throne!
Right, for a while
I had forgotten it.
Leave it to me!
I know what to do!
Hello, friend! I was just
dreaming that you were saving me!
You shouldn't have such foolish dreams!
You must sleep soundly.
I wonder if there is still
any child awake..!
I'm going to do a patrol.
Goodnight!
Sleep well, friends!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP